"아빠"
"dear dad,
앉아서 이걸 쓰면서
저와 아빠에 대해 생각하고 있어요
"as I sit down to write this, I'm thinking
about you and me.
제 머릿 속에서 끄집어내기 힘들지만
"there's one time in particular
특별했던 무렵이 있었어요
"that I can't get out of my head.
제가 가정부의 성냥개비를 가져다가는
"I took our housekeeper's matches
뒷뜰에 낙엽들을 모아다가 불을 질렀었죠
"and I set the leaves in the
backyard on fire.
그리고는 전 가정부 탓이라고 했어요
"then I tried to blame her.
물론 아빠는 머리 꼭대기에 있었죠
"you knew better, of course.
아빤 그 일을 제게 교훈을 주는 기회로 삼았어요
"and you used it as an opportunity to teach
me
거짓말을 하는 것과
거짓말쟁이가 되는 것의 차이점을요
"the difference between lying
and being a liar.
그날 배웠어요
아빠에게는 어떤 것이든
"I learned that day that I could
say anything to you,
해야 할 일이 무엇이든
말할 수 있다는 걸
"and that whatever we
had to deal with,
나에 대한 아빠의 사랑은 그대로라는 걸
"your love for me would
never go away.
그래서 아빠에게 이 편지를 쓰는 거예요
"I guess that's why I'm writing this to
you.
아빠랑 엄마가 절 걱정하시는 걸 알아요
"I know you and mom are
worried about me.
두분이 제가 대학입시를 실패해서
"I know you think I'm not handling college
well,
방황하는 거라고 생각하신다는 걸 알아요
"that I'm adrift.
그 말도 맞아요
"and I guess you're both right.
하지만 그보다는 좀 더 복잡해요
But it's a little more
complicated than that."
음
Mmm.
뭐 필요한 거 있니?
You need anything?
네 엄마가 잘 모르겠다더구나
Your mom wasn't sure that you would have
책 사고 나서 네게 돈이 충분히 남았는지
Enough money left after buying your books.
괜찮아요, 아빠
No, I'm fine, dad.
절 보러 먼 길을 오셔서 기뻤어요
"I'm so glad you came all the
way out to see me.
아빠가 바쁘신 걸 아니까요
"I know you're busy.
아빠에게 털어놓고 싶었어요
진짜 말하고 싶었어요
"and I wanted to talk to you,
really talk to you,
하지만 그럴 수 없었죠
"but I just couldn't.
그건 제 잘못이지, 아빠 잘못은 아니예요
"that's my fault, dad, not yours.
이제 모든 걸 말씀드리려고 해요
"so I'm going to say everything now.
불공평하다는 걸 알아요
"I know that's not fair.
제발 화내지는 마세요
"but please don't be too mad at me.
이건 지금 잠시동안 할 일에 대해
"this is something I've been thinking about
doing
생각해 온 거예요
"for a while now.
아셨음 해요
"and I want you to know
결국엔 일어났을 일이라는 걸요
That it would have happened no matter
what."
너무 혼란스러웠어요
"I've been so confused.
그리고 이 일은...그건.......
And this thing, it's..."
아리아나?
Arianna?
....그 모든 상황의 중앙에 있는 등대 같았어요
"...Like a lighthouse in the middle of all
that.
어디로 가야할지 쉬워진 거예요
"it's so easy to steer toward,
그게 목적지라고 생각해요
"that I feel like it's where I have to
go.
첫째로 드리고 싶은 말은 죄송해요
"the first thing I want to say is that I'm
sorry.
이게 아버지께 말씀드리고픈
마지막이기를 바라요
"I hope that, since this
is the last time
아빠가 필요한 걸 드릴 수 있어요
"I'm going to talk to you,
I can give you what you need
제 행동으로 결과를 보여줄 수 있어요
"to come to terms with
what I've done.
존경하고 사랑하는 아빠
"you're my dear dad.
아빠에겐 어떤 것이든 말할 수 있죠
그렇죠, 아빠?
I can say anything to you,
right, dad?"
어디 있니?
Hello?
아리!
Ari!
아리아나?
Arianna?
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
DC 기타미드갤/ 넬슨 하-하! / 피드백 환영
출발시간 5분전입니다
Departure time is t-minus five minutes.
DC 기타미드갤/ 넬슨 하-하! / 피드백 환영
승차하지 않은 사람은
If you're not on the train,
정거장에 남게 됩니다
You're going to be left at the station.
도와 드려요?
Can you help?
그래그래, 고맙다
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Thanks.
마리, 얘야
너 5분 남았다
Marie, honey, you got five minutes.
이 장을 끝내고 싶은데
I just want to finish this chapter.
그럼 차 안에서 마저 봐
Well, you can finish in the car.
엥, 이거 도서관 책이네?
Hey, is this a library book?
이거 어디서 났어?
Where'd you get this?
요새 도서관에 간 적이 없는데
We haven't been to the library in ages.
벽장에 있었어요
It was in my closet.
기한이 언제까지였지?
Well, when was it due?
몰라요, 내가 대출한 거 아닌데
I don't know. I didn't take it out.
그럼 누구야
Well, who did?
누구라고 생각하세요?
Who do you think?
누가 방 청소하다가
Well, somebody must have cleaned the room
대충 벽장에 뒀겠죠 뭐
And just stuck it in the closet.
누굴~까
Somebody?
브리짓, 네 책이 아니잖아
Bridge, that isn't your book.
도서관 소유야
It belongs to the library.
알아요, 책들을 반납하는 걸 까먹었나 봐요
Yeah, well, I guess I
forgot they were in there.
책들??
"they?"
그 안에 얼마나 더 있는데?
How many have you got in there?
몰라요
I don't know.
도서관에서는 한번에 7권을 빌려주니까요
I mean, they let you check
out seven at a time.
브리짓, 벽장에 기한 넘긴 책이
일곱 권이나 있다고?
Bridgette, you have seven
overdue books in your closet?
너 가지라고 도서관 책을 대출하는 게 아냐
You're not supposed to
take the library books,
반납했었어야지
You're supposed to bring them back.
지금은 너무 늦었잖아요
Well, it's too late now.
제가 그거 돌려줬다가
I mean, if I brought them back,
그 사람들이 절 감옥 같은 데 보내면 어떡해요
Then they would send me
to jail or something.
감옥에 보내진 않는단다
They're not going to send you to jail.
벌금을 물어야지
They're going to charge you a fine.
액수가 클텐데
I'm guessing it's going to be big.
내 직감으로는 네 용돈이 곧장
My hunch is your allowance
is going straight to
몇 달간 도서관에 바쳐지겠네
The public library for the next few months.
그치만 도서관 책은 무료잖아요
But library books are supposed to be free.
무료지, 네가 규정만 지키면
They are free, as long
as you play by the rules.
오늘 학교 파하고,
거기 가서
After school today,
I want you to walk over there
그 책들 반납하고 와
And return those books.
알았어요
Fine.
읽고 있는데!
I was reading that!
그래, 안됐다
Well, too bad.
도서관에서 대출해서 봐
Go check it out at the library.
여보세요
Hello.
날세
Morning.
아침부터 귀찮게 해서 미안하네
Um, sorry to bother you so early.
오, 아니에요
Oh, no, no, no.
염려마세요, 검사님
It's no bother, mr. District attorney.
부탁 좀 할까 하네만
I was wondering if I could ask a favor.
오늘 아침에 출근하러 오는 길에
Wondering if there was any way
I could get you to drop by
우리 집에 잠시 들러주게
My house on your way to work this morning,
한 9시쯤?
Say around 9:00?
물론이죠, 괜찮으신거죠?
Course. Is everything all right?
9시까지는 아무 것도 생각하기 어렵다네
Nothing that can't hold until 9:00.
12화. Dear Dad...
머리 멋지네요
Nice hair.
안경 멋진데요
Nice glasses.
자네들도 알겠지만
우리 딸 아리아나가
As you both know, our daughter
arianna took her own life
대학교 2학년 때 자살했었지
During her sophomore year of college.
오늘이 내가 그 애를 발견했던
Today is the anniversary
of the day she died,
그 애가 죽었던 기일이라네
The day I found her.
자식을 잃는다는 건......
Losing a child...
어느 부모에게나 악몽이죠
Is always a nightmare for any parent.
우리에겐 특히 힘든 일이었어요
For us, I think it's been
especially difficult.
아리아나는 유서 한 장 남기지 않았어요
Arianna didn't leave a note.
이유를 말해주지 않았죠
She never told us why.
전혀요?
Nothing at all?
아리아나는 한분에게라도 말을 안했었나요?
She never communicated
with either one of you?
릴리가 신문을 가지러 나갔다가
Lily went out to get the newspaper,
우편함에 깃발이 세워진 걸 보고
And saw that the flag was up on the mailbox.
안을 들여다 봤다가
And when she looked inside,
이걸 발견했다네
She found this.
세상에
Oh, no.
끔찍한 일이네요
This is terrible.
정말 유감이에요
I'm so sorry.
나야 확실하게 몇 년간
적들을 만들어왔지
I certainly made my share
of enemies over the years.
감옥에 수많은 나쁜 놈들을 집어 넣었고
Put plenty of bad people in prison,
심지어 죽이겠다는 협박도 받아 봤네만
Even received death threats,
이런 건 처음이라네
But never anything like this.
내 가족을 연관시킨 건 없었지
Never anything involving my family.
잠깐 실례해도 될까요
Would you please excuse me?
저... 미친 소리로 들리겠지만
You know, this is going to sound crazy.
누가 이랬는지 알 것 같아요
I think I saw the man who did this.
무슨 말인가?
What are you talking about?
우편함에 뭘 집어넣는 남자를 봤어요
I saw a man putting
something in your mailbox.
진짜 봤다는 건 아니고요
그 사람이 실제로 거기에 있던 건 아니라서
I mean, I didn't really see it,
and he wasn't really there,
하지만 그 땐 알아차리지 못했어요
But I didn't realize that at the time.
사실 그 사람 꽤나 똑똑히 봤어요
I actually got a pretty good look at him.
젊었고, 아마 서른쯤
He was young, maybe 30.
백인에다가 키도 크고 말랐어요
Caucasian, tall, thin.
이런 안경을 쓰고 있었어요
And he was wearing these glasses.
검은 뿔테같은 거요
Kind of... Black, vintage frames.
짐작가는 거라도?
Ring any bells?
생각이 안나는구먼
No, I don't think so.
좋아요 제가 할 일은
Okay, I'll tell you what--
누가 이 남자를 봤는지
I'm going to canvass the neighborhood,
이웃들을 조사하러 다닐게요
See if anyone else saw this guy.
그리고 경찰서에서 용의자를
I'm also going to have
someone at the station
검사님 사건파일에서 함께 대조해보죠
Put together a file of all your cases.
검거하려고 했던 용의자들 전부
사진첩도 보고
A mug-book of everyone you've tried.
만약 이걸 두고 간 놈이
정말로 검사님이 감방에 넣은 사람이라면
If the guy who left this
really is someone you put away,
그러면 다행히도
앨리슨이 그를 알아볼테니까요
Then, well, hopefully,
allison will recognize him.
꼬마 아가씨야, 이 책들 한참 지났어
Young lady, these books are very late.
일년 넘게 갖고 있었던 거야
You've had them for more than a year now.
알아요
I know.
아마 어따 뒀는지 까먹었었나 봐요
I, uh, guess I just kind
of lost track of them.
죄송해요
I'm sorry.
하지만 책들은 정말 좋았었어요
But they were really good.
그랬다니 다행이구만
Glad you thought so.
이제사 다른 애들이 책을 즐기겠구먼
Now maybe some other
children can enjoy them, too.
이미 도서관에서는 이 책들을 또 주문했어
I'm afraid we've already
forwarded these to collections.
너 소매가격으로 돈 물어야겠구나
You owe the retail cost of the books.
총 $92.18네
Which comes out to $92.18.
92달러요??!
Ninety-two dollars?!
전 어린애인데요!
I'm just a kid!
92달러가 어디서 나요?
Where am I supposed to get $92?
경찰에 신고하시려는 건 아니죠, 그렇죠?
Uh, you're not going to
call the police, are you?
저 체포돼나요?
Am I going to get arrested?
부모님에게 말씀드리는 건 어떠니?
What about asking your parents?
그러고 싶지 않아요
No. I don't want to do that.
이미 그분들은 제게 엄청 화내신걸요
They're already really mad at me.
내게 생각이 있는데
I might have an idea.
네가 도서관에서 일한다고???
You're working
At the library?
뭘 그리 놀래시나?
Why are you so surprised?
글쎄
I don't know.
그냥 이상해
It just seems odd
네가 뭘 하리라는 걸
신뢰하는 사람도 있다니
That someone would depend
on you to do anything.
왜이래, 나 믿음직해
Hey, I'm dependable.
게다가 도서관 사방에는
And besides, they've got books laying around
책이 널려 있는 걸
All over the place in there.
그러니 잘된거지
So this is good.
문제가 있는 사람들을 돕는거야
I'm helping them with their problem,
내게 돈을 주는 대신
벌금을 깎아주는 거지
And instead of paying me,
they're paying off the fines.
내게는 꽤나 괜찮은 해결법 같구나
It sounds like a pretty good
Solution to me.
저녁먹기 전에 아이스크림 먹지 마
Honey, don't eat any ice
cream before dinner.
언제 저녁먹는데요?
Well, when are we going to eat?
배고프단 말이에요
I'm hungry.
모르겠구나
I don't know.
좋은 질문이다
니네 엄마 어딨냐?
That's a good question. Where's your mom?
아까 몇시간 동안
She's been in her room
방에 계셨어요
For the past couple hours.
자기 배고파?
Hey, you hungry?
피자 좀 주문할까?
Should I order some pizzas?
아니아니, 냉장고에 남은 음식이 있어
No, no; we have some leftovers in the fridge
내가 데우려고 했는데
I was going to heat up.
미안, 이 파일들 좀 보느라고
I'm sorry, I got so caught up
With these files.
아직도 못찾았어?
Still no luck?
드발로스가 수감시킨 한사람 한사람 다 봤는데
I've looked through every single person
그 끔찍한 카드를 남긴 남자랑
That devalos ever put away,
and none of them look like
닮은 사람이 없어
The man I saw leave that awful card.
아마도 밤에는 접어둘 시간인게지
Well, maybe it's time to
pack it in for the night.
그럴까봐
I guess so.
내가 뭔가라도 할 수 있길 바랄 뿐이야
I just wish I could do something.
도왔으면 좋겠어
I wish I could help.
잠깐만
Well, wait a second.
자기 영매 아니던가?
Aren't you actually that psychic woman
경찰서에다 어...누가 그랬는지
범인 묘사해주는?
Who, uh, gave the police
A description of the guy who did this?
웃기네
Very funny.
이해가 안가는 게 뭔지 알아?
You know what I can't figure out?
피타고라스의 정리?
The pythagorean theorem?
어젯밤에 드발로스 검사님과
딸에 대해 꿈을 꿨거든
Last night, I had a dream about
devalos and his daughter.
꿈 속에서는 검사님이 유서를 발견했어
And in it, I saw him find a suicide note.
유서에서 뭐라고 말하는지 까지도 들었어
I even heard what the note said.
그러니까 대부분, 어쨌든
I mean, most of it, anyway.
하지만 내가 오늘 아침 그 집에 갔을 때는
But then when I went to
his house this morning,
아내가 말하기를 아리아나는
아무 것도 남긴 게 없대
His wife said that arianna
never left anything behind.
왜 그런 짓을 했을까?
Now, why would he do that?
왜 아내에게 그 사실을 숨기는걸까?
Why would he keep something
like that from her?
모를 일이네
I have no idea.
자기, 애들 데려올까?
Hey, you want to take the kids out?
야간학습시간인 거 알지만
I know it's a school night, but, you know,
애들 데려오면 재밌어질 거야
It might be fun to take the kids out.
배심원 여러분
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
어떤 변호사라도 사건을 맡으면서
No attorney relishes the prospect
젊은 여성에 대한 성폭행이 연관된
Of taking on a case
수임사건의 승소가능성을 기뻐하지 않습니다
That involves the sexual
assault of a young woman.
이 사건은 저희들에게
It forces us to ask uncomfortable questions
피고와 원고의 사적인 행위에 대해
About the personal behavior
불편한 질문을 던지게 하죠
Of both the alleged assailant
And the alleged victim.
이 사건에서 우리는
그날 밤 디애나 웨일른에게 일어난 일을
In this case, we will have to
look closely at what happened
면밀히 살펴봐야 합니다
물론 그녀의 진술대로라면요
On the night that deanna whalen,
by her own admission,
기꺼이 피고의 집까지 피고와 동행했었고
Willingly accompanied the
defendant back to his home.
그 후 그들은 섹스를 했죠
한번도 아니고 두 번도 아니고
That they had sex not once, not twice,
저녁동안 세 번을 한 걸
But three times over the
course of the evening
논의하자는 게 아닙니다
Is not in dispute.
아직까진 웨일른씨는
범죄가 저질러진 거라고 주장하지만
And yet, miss whalen maintains
that a crime has been committed.
그녀가 다음날 피고에게 전화번호도 줬다는 거
That she gave him her
phone number the next day
역시 논쟁점은 아닙니다
Is also not in dispute.
하지만 그녀는 여전히 사건이 벌어진 저녁에
But still, she claims that she
was not a willing participant
본인이 자발적으로 한 게 아니라고 주장합니다
In the previous evening's events.
심지어 웨일른씨는 경찰에 신고하기까지
Miss whalen even concedes
that it took her three days
3일이 걸렸다고 시인했죠
Before deciding to call the police.
지금은 그녀가 불가항력했음을 증언하고 있습니다
And now she cites her inability
사건이 있던 저녁을 회상하면서 말하기를
To recall the precise events
of the evening as proof
거윈씨가 그녀에게 약을 먹이고
강간했었을거라는 군요
That mr. Gerwin must have
drugged her and raped her.
그럴수도 있겠죠
Quite a story.
하지만 추측이 전부입니다
But that's all it is.
꾸며낸 이야기입니다
A story.
지방 검사도 그 사실을 압니다
And the district attorney knows it.
검찰에서는 피고인을
야비한 남자로 묘사하려고 하지만
Now, the prosecution will
attempt to portray the defendant
사실은 그렇지 않습니다
As a man of low character, but he is not.
검찰은 제 변론을
웨일른씨를 공격한 것으로
덧칠하려고 하지만
They will paint my argument
as an attack on miss whalen,
그렇지 않습니다
But it is not.
사실을 말씀드리자면
제 고객은 무죄입니다
Truth be told, my client
is guilty of nothing more
합의 하에 섹스를 한 게 죄라면
Than participating in consensual sex,
웃긴 건 말입니다 그러면 고소인도 같이 유죄인거죠
And the irony is,
his accuser is guilty of the same.
하지만 그녀는 이 법정을 이용하고 있습니다
And yet, she seeks to use this court
당신과, 여기 배심원들을
법적 면죄부로써
And you, this jury,
as a kind of legal absolution,
그녀의 죄를 씻기 위한 방편으로써
As a way to wash away her sins
그래야 죄에 대한 부담감이 필요없으니까요
So she needn't take responsibility for them.
그러면 유일한 문제가 있습니다
There's only one problem with that.
윌리암 거윈은 강간범이 아닙니다
William gerwin is not a rapist.
윌리암 거윈은 결백한 사람입니다
William gerwin is an innocent man.
맞아, 그 사람 맞아
Yep. That's definitely him.
분명히 윌리암 거윈이군
That's definitely william gerwin.
과거에 로펌에서
Back when I worked
피고인측 변호사로 일했을 때지
As a defense attorney at mcclenahan-everett,
거윈씨는 내 고객 중의 하나였지
Mr. Gerwin was one of my clients.
실제로는 훨씬 중요한 고객이었지
A rather important one, actually.
경영자 중 한명의 아들이었거든
He was the son of one of the partners.
기소될 당시 22살이었지
He was 22 when he was accused
파티에서 만난 젊은 여자를
약을 타서 강간한 혐의였어
Of drugging and raping a young
woman that he met at a party.
피해자의 이름은 디애나 웨일른
Her name was deanna whalen.
거윈의 아버지는 내게 개인적으로 청했지
Gerwin's father personally asked me
아들내미 사건 잘 부탁한다고
To take his son's case as a favor.
그리고....
And...
기꺼이 수락했다네
I was only too happy to oblige.
사건은 별 거 없었어
The case was very weak.
전형적인 “그와 그녀의 이야기”였고
A classic "he-said, she-said."
강간 검사는 절대 실행되지 않았어
Rape kit was never administered.
여자 주변에서 약이 발견되지도 않았고
No drugs were found in the girl's system.
사건 후에 그녀는 며칠이 지나기까지
She didn't even file a
report with the police
경찰에 신고장을 제출하지도 않았지
Until several days after
the alleged incident.
거윈씨의 기소를 맡았던 부검사는 알았지
The ada who was handling
gerwin's prosecution
공산이 그에게 불리하다라는 걸
Knew the odds were against him,
그는 내게 초반에 거래를 제안했어
And he offered me a deal early on,
하지만 난 거절했다네
But I-I turned it down.
그 사건에 자신이 있었거든
That's how confident I was in the case.
그 사건 저도 기억나네요
I remember that case.
그 남자애 감옥에 가지 않았나요?
That kid wound up going to jail, didn't he?
누군가 비디오 컬렉션을 보냈지
Someone sent a collection of videos
재판 중에
To the district attorney's office
지방검사 사무실에 말일세
In the middle of the trial.
누군지는 밝혀내지 못했지만
Never found out who sent them,
그게 중요한 건 아니었지
But it didn't much matter.
비디오 내용은
윌리엄이 촬영한 건데
They were videos that
william had made of himself
의식이 없고 약에 취한 여성들을
능욕하는 거였다네
Having sex with unconscious
and obviously drugged women,
디애나 웨일른도 거기 있었지
Including deanna whalen.
제안받았던 거래는
The deal I'd been offered
슉 날라가게 됐다네
Evaporated.
윌리엄은 최고형을 받았고
William was given the maximum sentence,
얼마 안가서 나는 로펌을 그만 뒀다네
And I left mcclenaha
n-everett shortly after that.
유감이네요, 검사님
I-I'm sorry, sir.
그 사람이 최고형을 받았다면
If he received a maximum sentence,
어떻게 그 카드를 남길 수 있는거죠?
Then how could he be the
one to leave you that card?
최근에 일찍 가석방 허가를 받았다더군
Turns out, he was recently
granted an early parole.
감방동기가 그를 믿고는
It seems that one of his cell mates
풀리지 않은 살인사건의 디테일을
Took him into his confidence one night,
그를 믿고 어느 날 밤 말해줬다는군
Told him the details of an unsolved murder,
조직범죄에 관련된 거였나 봐
Something to do with organized crime.
연방법원 사건이라
It was a federal case,
거윈은 지역 FBI 사무소에 가서
So gerwin went to the local fbi office.
비밀증언의 대가로 교환했대
And in exchange for his sealed testimony,
감형 받은 거지
Time was shaved off his sentence.
내가 아는 바로는
As I understand it,
거윈은 공개법정에 나간 적도
Gerwin never even had to appear
없다는군
In open court.
거윈을 감옥에 보낸 사람은
The man gerwin sent to jail
누가 그에게 제안을 했는지 알지 못했지
Never even knew who offered him up.
우편함에 카드를 넣은 남자가 거윈이라는 게
And you're absolutely
certain that william gerwin
자네가 확실히 본 거 맞는건가?
Is the man you saw put this card in the box?
그 사람 맞아요, 검사님
It was him, sir.
확실해요
I'm sure of it.
이미 가석방 담당자에게 연락을 했습니다
I already reached out to his parole officer.
거윈씨를 데려와서
몇시간 동안 심문해보죠
We're bringing gerwin in for
questioning in a few hours.
그 사람이 정말로 우편함에
카드를 놓고 간 사람이라면
If he really was the one who
left that note in your mailbox,
얘기 좀 해보는 거죠
Well, let's just say
그가 또 남기지 않도록
제가 확실히 할 작정입니다
I intend to make damn sure
he doesn't leave another.
839.2...
우와
짱이다
Whoa. Cool.
에이킨 선생님
저 사람 누구예요?
Miss aiken, who's that guy?
별 사람 없는데
Oh, nobody special.
컴퓨터 쓰려고 매일 도장찍는 사람이야
Just a fellow who comes in
every day to use the computers.
"프린스"?
"prince"?
아뇨, 이런 카드 본 적이 없는데요
No, I've never seen this card before.
진짜로 드발로스씨에게 이런 걸 남기지 않았어요
I certainly didn't leave it for mr. Devalos.
그럼, 이제 된 건가요?
So, is that it?
가도 됩니까?
Can I go now?
아직 아닙니다, 거윈씨
Not just yet, mr. Gerwin.
그렇군요
Okay.
하고 싶은 말이 더 있나 봐요?
So what else do you want to talk about?
“진짜 남자”는 잘 살고 있나요, 그럼?
How is the "man-man" doing, anyway?
제 아버지가 그를 부르곤 할 때 하던 말이죠
That's what my dad used to call him.
드발로스씨는 별로 안좋아했지만
당신들이 뭘 할 수 있을까요, 안 그래요?
Manny didn't like it very much,
but what can you do, right?
뭐, 즐거워 보이는 군요
Well, you seem to be
having a pretty good time.
만약 드발로스씨의 우편함에
What would you say
당신이 카드를 놓아둔 걸
If I told you that we had an anonymous tip
본 사람들이 있다고 한다면
From someone who says that they saw you
뭐라고 하겠습니까?
Put that card in devalos's mailbox?
제가 처음 할 말은 이거죠
"누군지 몰라도 틀렸수"
Well, the first thing I'd say is,
"your tipster is mistaken."
하지만 그가 틀리지 않았다 쳐도
But even if he or she weren't,
ㅆㅂ 융통성 없게 사는 놈인가?
What's with the hard-ass routine?
제 말은 이 카드를 누가 남겼든간에
그게 불법이냐고요
I mean, whoever left this card,
did they do something illegal?
축하카드를 보내는 걸
금지하는 법이라도 있나요?
Is there a law against mailing
people greeting cards?
남 괴롭히는 걸 막는 법이 있죠
There are laws against harassment.
이 카드가 법을 망치기라도 하나요?
And does this card break that law?
거윈씨, 지금 가석방중이죠?
Mr. Gerwin, you're on parole, right?
우리가 원한다면, 당신 삶을
아주 골치 아프게 할 수도 있어요
If we want to, we can make
life very difficult for you.
그러니 한 짓을 인정하는 게 어떻습니까
So why don't you just admit what you did,
그래서 오늘 이 일을 끝내버립시다
And we can get this thing cleared up today?
제가 안했으니까요
Because I didn't do it.
그의 집에 간 적도 없어요
I've never been to his house.
몇 년간 그 사람을 생각해본 적도 없습니다
I haven't thought about him in years.
그게 확실해요?
You sure about that?
그 “진짜 남자”는 당신 변호사였잖아요
The "man-man" was your lawyer.
유죄 판결을 받았고
You got convicted.
원한이 없다 이거죠?
You're not holding a grudge?
제가 왜 원한을 갖습니까?
Why would I hold a grudge?
여자 강간한 거 맞는데요
I raped that girl.
감옥에 갔고
I went to jail.
제가 왜 제 변호사에게 화를 내겠습니까?
Why would I be mad at my attorney?
당신같이 부잣집 자식들은
Rich kid like you
감옥 안에서 지내기가 힘들었을텐데요
Probably had a pretty
rough go of it in prison.
놀라지 않겠습니다
당신만의 약에 대한 취향을 가졌더라도
I wouldn't be surprised
if you got a little taste
한번이나 두번쯤은요
Of your own medicine, once or twice.
한번이나 두 번이요?
Once or twice?
몇 년간 저만의 약을 먹으면서 보냈죠
I spent years getting "
a taste of my own medicine."
그게 듣고 싶습니까?
That what you wanted to hear?
음이 있으면 양도 있다는 거요?
That there's a ying for every yang?
제가 받은 자업자득이요?
That I got what I deserve?
뭐 그런 거죠
Well... There it is.
자, 이 카드가 당신들 보스를 열받게 했다면
Now, if this card upset your boss,
당신들에게 뭘 말해야 할지 모르겠네요
I don't know what to tell you.
나요?
But me?
새로운 나요?
The new me?
제가 확실히 믿는 건 말입니다
당신이 이런 카드를 받았다면
I'm a firm believer that if
you get a card like this,
어쩌면 인과응보란 거죠
You probably deserved it.
그러니 당신들은 상사를 앉혀놓고
So maybe you should be
sitting your boss down,
물어봐요
왜 내게 이런 일이 일어났을지
Asking him why he thinks he got this.
한대 치고 싶더라
He was so smug.
사실상 그 놈이 그가 저지른 사실로
He was practically rubbing our noses
우리들에게 창피를 줬어
In the fact that he did it.
당신이 그에게 넘겨준 셈이 됐네
Well you've got to hand it to him.
주목받을 방법을 알아낸거지
He figured out a way to get attention.
당신 상사를 열받게 만드는 걸로
To work out his anger at your boss.
하지만 그 사람은 가석방중이니까
But he's on parole, right?
사실상 아무 것도 할 수 없어
He's essentially impotent.
만약 무슨 짓을 했다간
바로 감옥에 들어가게 될 걸
If he does anything,
he goes right back to jail.
그러니 그 사람이 카드를 보낸다면
So he-he sends that card.
수많은 사람들을 열받게 하는 일이니까
He gets a rise out of a bunch of people.
하는 짓이 아동틱하지 않아?
It's kind of like a child, don't you think?
아동?
Like a child?
그 사람은 십대 소녀를 강간했어
He raped a teenage girl,
그리곤 빠져 나갈 수 없게 되니까
And when he couldn't get away with it,
변호사를 탓하는 거야
He blamed his lawyer.
여기에 아동스러운 게 뭐가 있어
There's nothing childlike about that.
아빠? 컴퓨터 좀 봐주실래요?
Uh, dad? Can you come look at the computer?
남아서 속 좀 끓여봐
맥주 마저 마시라규
Stay. Stew. Finish your beer.
원한다면 내 맥주도 마셔주라
Finish my beer, if you like.
이것 좀 보세요
갑자기 이메일이 2백통이나 왔어요
I mean, look at this.
Suddenly, I have 200 e-mails
오늘 아침엔 없었는데
That I didn't have this morning.
부동산 팔아서 6배나 벌고 싶은 마음도 없어요
I mean, I don't want to earn
six figures selling real estate
내 여가 시간에 말이에요
In my spare time. I don't care
제 차가 엎어지지 않는 한
중고차 현금보상으로 5천달러 버는 일따위
About getting $5,
000 from "cash for clunkers"
신경 쓰고 싶지 않아요
Without even turning in my car.
여기 “프린스 아반투” 말도 듣고 싶지 않아요
And I don't want to hear from
this "prince abantu" again
2천만 달러 상속재산을
어떻게 못받게 됐는지 따위요
About how he can't get at
his $20 million inheritance.
방금 아반투 왕자 어쩌구 했어?
Did you guys say something
about prince abantu?
스팸방지 프로그램 최근거로
업데이트 했니?
Did you download the latest
version of spam blocker?
아뇨, 아무 것도 다운받지 말라면서요
그래서 안했죠
No. You told me not to
download anything, so I didn't.
그래, 비켜봐
Okay. Scoot over.
내가 좀 조작해보자
Let me drive for a minute.
누가 아반투 왕자 어쩌구 하지 않았어?
Did someone say something
about prince abantu?
맞아. 왜?
Yeah. Why?
나 그 사람 아는 것 같아
I think I know him.
네가 어떻게 알아
가상의 인물인데
You don't know him. He's not real.
순진한 사람들한테
동결재산을 복구하게 도와달라고 하는
I mean, he's a scammer who
claims to be a nigerian prince
자칭 나이지리아 왕자 사기꾼이야
Who needs help recovering
frozen assets from some trust.
그러니까 네가 그 사람에게 만달러를 주면
I mean, it's like, you give him $10,000,
너한테 백만달러를 준다고 하는 거지
And he gives you a million.
아니, 언니가 틀렸어
No. You're wrong.
프린스 아반투는 진짜 사람이야
Prince abantu's a real guy.
내가 일하는 도서관에 오는데
He goes to the library where I work.
언니가 원한다면 그 사람을 만나볼 수도 있어
You can come visit him, if you want.
그 사람은 항상 거기 있거든
I mean, he's there all the time.
나라면 그거 삭제 안할거야
And I wouldn't delete that if I were you.
우리가 할 일은
그에게 돈을 좀 보내는 거야
All we have to do is
just send him some money,
그럼 우린 더 큰 집으로 이사할 수 있어
And then we can move into a bigger house.
브리짓
Bridgette.
내 보기엔 사기꾼같지 않아
He doesn't look like a scammer to me.
왕자처럼 보여
예복을 입고 있단 말이야
He looks like a prince.
I mean, he wears robes,
그 사람은 커다란 지팡이를 갖고 다니고....
And he carries this big stick thing and...
네가 누굴 봤는지 모르겠구나, 얘야
I don't know who you saw, sweetie,
이번 일엔 애리얼 편이야
But I got to side with ariel on this one.
이 수법은 고전적인 사기수법이거든
This is one of the oldest
tricks in the book.
이런 편지를 백통 넘게 받아 봤는데
I've gotten 100 e-mails like this.
돈을 보낸 사람들은
People who send them aren't connected
아프리카 왕자랑 연결되지 못할 거야
To african royalty
어쨌든 어떤 형태든 간에
그 사람들은 범죄자란다
In any way, shape, or form;
they're just criminals.
알았어요. 하지만 아빠가 틀렸어요
Okay, but I think you're wrong.
오케이
Okay.
그냥 봐서는 모르게
침실 선반에 있더군
They were on a shelf in the bedroom;
hidden in plain sight.
확실히 경찰들은 귀찮았는지
그의 집을 수색할 때
Obviously, the cops never
bothered to actually look
비디오들을 자세히 안봤나봐
At the tapes when they searched his place.
내 부하들은 안 그렇지
처음으로
My people didn't, either,
the first time through.
자네가 다시 살펴보라고
나를 보냈던 건 잘된 일이야
It's a good thing you sent
me to take a second look.
들여다보게
Look inside.
이거 내가 생각하는 그거 맞나?
Is this what I think it is?
한번 보게
Take a look.
여기 좀 마셔봐
조금만 마셔봐
Here, have some of this.
Have a little drink.
으, 안할래....
Um, I don't...
그래?
No?
Uh, no. No?
기분이 안좋아
I don't feel so good.
그으래?
No?
그래? 응?
No. No?
기분이 별로야
No, I don't feel so good.
으으응?
No?
아.....
Oh...
다른 것도 마찬가지야
The others are just as bad.
여자만 달라지고 반복해
Different girls, same drill.
내가 찾을 거라고 기대하진 않았다는 걸 아네
I know it's not what you were
하지만 적어도 이제 자네도 알게 된 거지
Hoping I'd find, but at least now you know.
준비가 됐겠지
만약 빼도 박도 못하게 기소할
You'll be ready if there are
other copies floating around
다른 복사본들이 돌아다닌다면 말일세
For the prosecution to latch onto.
내가 하기를 원하는 건가
You want me
이것들을 우연히
To accidentally drop these
소각장에 떨어뜨려놓기를?
In an incinerator?
아니. 어.... 괜찮네
No, that's, uh, that's not necessary.
내가 처리하지
I'll take care of them.
고맙네, 월터
Thank you, walter.
나 지금 본인 사건을 일부러 망친
드발로스를 얘기하는 거라니까
I'm telling you manuel devalos
torpedoed his own case.
내가 만났던 사람 중에서 최고로 정직한
Manuel devalos, the most honest, ethical man
윤리남 마누엘 드발로스를
I've ever met.
당신이 아는 두 번째 최고 정직남은 아니고?
Not the second-most honest and
ethical man you've ever met?
아놔, 조
Oh, come on, joe.
그분이 왜 그랬을까?
Why would he do that?
나야 모르지
I don't know.
아마도, 어쩌면 자신이 변호하는 사람이
Maybe, maybe 'cause he knew
유죄이기 때문일지도?
The guy he was representing was guilty?
부잣집 망나니를 변호하는 게 역겨웠을 수도
Maybe he was sick of representing rich scum.
도처에 깔린 변호사들에게
명성을 주고 싶었는지도
Or maybe he just wanted to give
lawyers everywhere a good name.
아니, 미안하지만
No, I'm sorry.
다 설명이 안돼
None of that explains it.
양심상 의뢰인을 대리할 수 없었다면
If he couldn't represent his
client in good conscience,
사건에서 손 떼면 되는 거였잖아
Then he should have just
resigned from the case.
그가 한 행동은 변호사-의뢰인 특권을 위반한거였어
What he did was a violation
of attorney-client privilege.
그건 불법이었다고
Hell, what he did was illegal.
하지만 당신 그 일로 그를 존경같은 거 하지 않아?
But don't you kind of admire him for it?
악당, 위험한 사람
A bad man, a dangerous man,
자유의 몸이 되느냐
감옥을 가느냐
Who might otherwise have
walked free, went to jail.
미안하지만 난 드발로스 편이야
Sorry. I'm on team devalos.
그래 사실을 말하자면
Yeah, well, if the truth be told,
나도 마찬가지야
So am I.
하지만 왜 내가 이 꿈을 꾼 걸까?
But why am I dreaming this?
내가 뭘 해야 하는 걸까
What am I supposed to do with it?
오랫동안 이 쉬운 말을 기다렸지
I've been waiting for one
this easy for a long time.
아무 것도 하지마
You do nothing.
그리고 당신은 검사님을 조금만 더 존경하라구
And you admire your boss
just a little bit more.
난 뭘 해야할 지 알아
I know I do.
당신은 아무 것도 말 안하는 거야
And you definitely don't say anything
이 일을 아무에게도
To anybody about this.
그게 당신이 할 일이지
That's what you do.
왔어요?
Hey.
들러줘서 고마워요
Thanks for coming by.
별일 없는 거죠?
Everything okay?
솔직히 말하자면, 모르겠어요
Honestly, I'm not sure.
이상한 일이라서요
This is a weird one.
제니퍼 러드로라는 여자가 여길 임대했는데
A girl named jennifer
ludlow rents this place.
바텐더예요
She's a bartender.
전문대 학생이고요
Community college student.
어젯밤에 남친 집에서 잤는데
Slept at her boyfriend's place last night.
오늘 아침 일찍 오고나서
Gets home early this morning,
저렇게 된 문을 발견했대요
Finds the door like that.
누군가 집안으로 강제로 들어오려고 했나 봐요
Someone forced their way into her place.
그 여자는 괜찮아요?
But she's all right?
네, 괜찮아요.
여기 아무도 없었으니까요
Oh, yeah, she's fine; there was no one here.
분실한 물건도 없고요
There's nothing missing, either.
그럼 우리 여기서 뭐하고 있는 거예요?
So what are we doing here?
누가 방에 있는 액자마다
Someone put one of these
이것들을 놓고 갔어요
In every picture frame in the place.
제가 물을게요
무슨 일인 거죠?
Okay, I'll ask. What is this?
확실하게 말할 수는 없지만
Can't say for sure.
누군지 드발로스에게 전할 말이 있는 거 같군요
Seems like someone's trying
to send manny a message.
무슨 생각하는지 알아요
우리 친구 윌리엄 거윈이죠
I know what you're thinking:
Our friend william gerwin.
문제는 현장이 깨끗하다는 겁니다
The problem is the scene's clean.
아직까지는 물리적 증거를 아무것도 찾지 못했어요
So far, we haven't found any
physical evidence at all.
이웃들도 본 게 없다고 하고요
None of the neighbors saw anything.
잡아들일 수 없어요
We got bupkis.
검사님도 이 사실을 알아요?
Does devalos know about this?
알고 싶지 않아 했죠
He didn't want to come down.
그저 말하기를 “말해줘서 고맙네”
Just said, "thanks for telling me."
마음이 산란한 듯 보였어요
Seemed kind of distracted.
하여튼 둘러 봐요
Anyway, feel free to look around.
뭐 발견하면 알려주고요
And holler if you get a bite.
물론이죠
Of course.
마누엘 드발로스의 음성사서함입니다
You've reached the voicemail
of manuel devalos.
메시지를 남겨주세요
Please leave a message,
최대한 빨리 회신하겠습니다
And I'll get back to you as
soon as I can. Take this.
검사님, 이거 확인하면 전화 주시겠어요?
Sir, can you give me a
call when you get this?
제니퍼 러드로의 아파트를 떠나는 중인데요
I'm just leaving that woman
jennifer ludlow's apartment.
안타깝지만, 도움이 될 만한 거
Unfortunately, I didn't see anything
아무 것도 못 봤어요
That could be of any help,
하지만 검사님의 옛 고객에 대해서
드릴 말씀이 있어요
But I do need to talk to
you about your old client.
또 보네요
We meet again.
당신이 그랬지
You did this.
뭐라고요?
내가 뭘 해요?
Sorry? Did what?
순진한 척 하지 마요
Don't play coy.
당신이 저지른 일, 왜 그랬는지도
우린 알고 있잖아요
We both know what you're doing
and why you're doing it.
정말이요?
Really?
이유도 안다고요?
You know why?
그 사건 때문이라면
Well, if that's the case,
나와 내 법적 변호인에게 벌어졌던 일이
If you really know what went on with me
무엇인지 진짜 안다면
And my legal representation,
그렇담 내 분노를 공유할 수 있겠구만요
Then I'm sure you share my sense of outrage.
이것 봐요 난
See, I think I deserve
모든 기소된 시민들이 누려야할 거를 누려야 했죠
What every other accused citizen deserves:
공정한 재판 말입니다
A fair trial.
말인즉슨 검찰 일이 수월하도록
And that means having a defense
attorney who's not serving me up
나를 돕지 않는 피고쪽 변호사를 뜻하죠
On a silver platter to the prosecution.
뭘 원하는데요?
What do you want?
이 사람을 괴롭혀서 뭐가 달라지는데요?
How is harassing this man
gonna change anything?
내가 기소된 후에 내 가족이
Are you aware that after I was convicted,
나와 인연을 끊은 걸 아나요?
My family disowned me?
사실입니다
It's true.
감옥에서 썩은 거 뿐만 아니라
So not only did I spend
all those years in prison,
아무 것도 아니게 된거요
I came out with nothing.
중죄인에 무일푼이죠
I'm a convicted felon. And I'm penniless.
그 사람---당신의 보스는
That man-- your boss--
나를 파멸시켰어요
He destroyed me.
원하는 게 뭐냐고요?
So what do I want?
그 사람을 깨부수고 싶은 거 같은데요
I guess I'd like to destroy him.
앞에 나와서 자기가 한 짓을 인정하길 바라요
I want him to come forward
and admit what he did.
직장을 잃길 바라고요
I want him to lose his job.
감옥에 갔으면 싶네요
And I want him to go to jail.
말도 안돼요
Well, that's crazy.
그런 일은 없을 거예요
That's never gonna happen.
그럴 수 있을 걸요
Oh, I think it might.
그 사람이 오늘 아침에
You know, I was really hoping
여길 나와 보기를
진정으로 바라고 있었어요
That manny was gonna come
down here this morning.
하지만 당신은 그 사람과 가까운 것 같군요
But you seem pretty close to him.
날 위해서 그 사람에게
메시지를 전해줄 수 있겠어요
Maybe you could give him a message for me.
제니퍼 러드로의 아파트에
그 기사들을 도배한 이유가 있어요
There's a reason why all
those articles wound up
In jennifer ludlow's apartment.
그녀는 젊고 예쁘죠
She's young, pretty.
딱 내 타입이에요
Just my type.
무슨 말인지
I don't understand.
조만간에
Sometime soon,
지방검사가 앞에 나와서
If the district attorney
doesn't come forward
본인이 한 짓을 인정하지 않는다면
And admit what he did,
제니퍼 러드로를 강간할 겁니다
I'm gonna rape jennifer ludlow.
무슨 말이라도 해야죠
You should say something.
참말로 미쳤군요
You really are insane.
당신말야 그렇게 협박하는 행위가
You know, the act of just
making that threat is
가석방 위반이라는 거 알죠?
A violation of your parole?
감옥에 돌아갈 거예요
You're going back to jail.
그렇게 생각 안해요
I don't think so.
음성녹음기라도 있어요?
Are you wearing a tape recorder?
내가 협박을 한 거냐고 누가 묻는다면
'cause if anyone asks if I made the threat,
부인할 거니까요
I'll deny it.
당신은 그 여자 근처에도 못 갈 거예요
You'll never get near that that girl.
그녀를 보호할 경찰들이 있거든요
We will have people protecting her.
당신을 감시할 경찰ㄷ 있고요
We'll have people following you.
네, 좋아요 하지만
얼마나 가까이 있을 수 있는데요?
Yeah, okay, but how close can they get?
어디든지 날 감시할 수 있대요?
Can they follow me everywhere?
지금 당장 누가 날 미행한대도
If someone were following me right now,
그 사람들이 날 막을 수 있을 거라고 생각해요? 예를 들면--
Do you really think they
could stop me from, say, uh,
당신 목을 부러뜨려도?
Breaking your neck?
만약 내가 잡히는 걸 신경쓰지 않았다면
If I didn't care about getting
caught, that is, and...
안 그랬을 겁니다
I don't.
알겠어요
Look, I get it.
당신, 같이 일하는 경찰들
You and the people you work with,
당신은 당신 할 일을 하시고요
You're gonna do what you're gonna do.
당신은 저 예쁜 제니퍼를 지켜보고요
You'll be watching pretty little jenny
이 예쁜 나도 감시하고요
And you'll be watching pretty little me.
아마도 그녀가 될 수도 있고
So maybe it'll be her.
다른 사람이 당할 수도 있죠
Maybe it'll be someone else.
중요한 건 드발로스가
The important thing is is that devalos knows
이 인과관계를 알게 되냐는 거죠
About all this ahead of time.
만약 그가 순리대로 하지 않는다면
That way, if he doesn't step up,
내가 찾은 여자는
The girl I find...
내 희생자가 되는 게 아니라
She won't just be my victim,
드발로스의 희생자인 게죠
She'll be his victim, too.
꽤 괜찮죠?
Pretty good, right?
그게 그를 죽이는 방법이죠
안 그래요?
That'll kill him, won't it?
드발로스같이 좋은 사람을
Good man like devalos.
존경받는 사람을
Respected man.
스스로 살기 싫을 겁니다
No way he'll be able to live with himself
그가 이 일이 일어나도록 둔다면 말입니다
If he let's that happen.
전 당신이 누군지 알아요.
I know who you are, you know.
뭐라고요?
Pardon me?
당신이 왕자라는 걸 알아요
I know you're a prince.
무슨 문제인지도 알아요
I know about the problem.
돈 문제를 알아요
내가 돕고 싶어요
I know about the money,
and I want to help you.
제가 가진 최대치가 38달러 좀 넘는데요
I've got a little more than $38 saved up.
많진 않지만
이제 전부예요
But I know it's not much,
but it's what I've got.
사람들에게 편지쓰는 걸로
And when you get all that money
당신이 돈을 모두 모으면
That you've been writing to people about,
다시 갚으세요
You can pay me back.
전 단지 도서관에 빚진
I just want enough
$92.18를 갚고 싶어요
To cover my library debt: $92.18.
착각했나 보구나, 꼬마야
I think you are mistaken, little girl.
다른 사람이랑 나를 혼동했네
You've got me mixed up with somebody.
나한테는 연기 안해도 돼요
You don't have to pretend with me.
왕자님이라는 거 알거든요?
I know you're a prince, okay?
이메일을 읽었어요
I've read the e-mails.
당신에게 도처에 적이 있다는 거 알아요
And I know that you have enemies everywhere,
전 적이 아니랍니다
But I'm not one of them.
보세요, 아저씨가 돈을 도로 못찾는대도
And look, even if you don't
get all your money back,
이걸 가지셨으면 좋겠어요
I want you to have this.
미안하다, 꼬마야
사람 잘못 봤어
I'm sorry, young lady,
but you've got me mixed up.
가야겠군
I must get going.
안돼요. 내 돈을 받지 않는 이유가
No, you can't just not take my money
내가 꼬마이기 때문이라면
공정하지 않아요
Because I'm a little kid; that's not fair.
그래 그래 알았다
Okay, okay, fine.
내게 다오
Okay, give it to me.
좀 이르지 않아요?
Isn't it a little early?
아니, 뭐냐면 좀 겁이 나서....
No, what it is, is... A little cowardly.
이기적인 거지
What it is, is selfish.
자네 타이밍이 칼 같구먼
Your timing is impeccable.
깔끔한 비상구를 만드는 중이었지
I was a minute from making a clean getaway.
비서가 어디 가야 당신을
찾을 수 있을지 말해줬어요
Your assistant told me
where I could find you.
검사님....
Sir...
얘기 좀 해요 진짜로
We really need to talk.
그러니까 내가 할 일은
이 미친놈을 막기 위해서는
So all I have to do to prevent this lunatic
출두해서 “내가 범죄자다”
From keeping his promise is step forward
선언하라는 약속을 지키는 거군?
And declare myself a criminal?
그 사람은 검사님이 한 일을 알아요
He knows what you did, sir.
어떻게 아는지는 모르겠지만, 그는 알아요
I don't know how he knows, but he knows.
저도 알고요
And I know it, too.
검사님이 한 일에 대해 비판하지 않을 겁니다
Look, I would never secon
d-guess what you did.
저였어도 그랬을 거예요
I might have done the same thing.
얼마나 많이 잃어야 하는지 알아요
And I know how much you stand to lose.
제가 모르는 게 있는 거 아니면
But unless there's something I'm not seeing,
검사님이 이 비밀을 더 이상
간직할 수 있을 거라고 생각안해요
I don't think you can keep
this a secret much longer.
과거를 사람들에게 말해야 할 것 같아요
I think you need to start
telling people what you did.
그 놈에게 굴복하지 않기 위해서요
And not to give in to him...
그 사람이 하고 싶은 대로 하게 하면
But to keep him from doing something
검사님이 회복하지 못할 겁니다
That you would never recover from.
그러니까....
I mean...
만약 그가 누군가 다치게 한다면.....
If he hurt some girl...
검사님이 그 일로 버틸 수 있을지요
I don't think you could live with that.
자네가 모르는 게 많다네, 앨리슨
There's a lot you're not seeing, allison.
걱정해주는 건 고맙네
But I appreciate your concern.
검사님
Uh, sir?
지금은 저도 이 일의 일부분인데요
Sir, I'm a part of this, too, now.
그러고 싶진 않지만 그런걸요
I don't want to be, but I am.
만약 출두하지 않는다면....
If you don't come forward...
모르겠어요
제가 해야 할 수도 있어요
I don't know, I might have to.
그럼 우리 각자 해야 할 일을 하겠구먼
Well, I guess we're each
gonna do what we have to do.
아빠에겐 무슨 말이든 할 수 있어요
그렇죠?
I can say anything to you,
right, dad?
이게 마지막이에요
아빠가 아셔야 할 건
Well, this is the last thing
you need to know,
절대로 저를 도울 수 없었을 거라는 걸요
The thing you're never gonna get
To help me deal with.
이 일은 내 안에 숨겨 왔던 거예요
This thing that's been
living inside me,
이 먹구름은 빠져 나갈 수 없어요
This cloud that I can't get out from
under,
항상 거기 있어 왔고
더 나빠지기 시작했어요
It's always been there,
but it started to get worse
고등학교 3학년때 일이었어요
During my senior year of high school.
킴이랑 저는 이 파티에 오게 됐어요
Kim and I went to this party.
크리스마스 명절을 보내는, 대부분 대학생이었어요
It was mostly college kids home
for their christmas break.
거기 한 남자애가 있었죠
There was a boy there.
걔 이름은 윌리엄
His name was william.
좀 나이가 있었지만 귀엽고 재미있었죠
He was a little older, cute, funny.
그가 마음에 들어서
나도 성인인 것처럼 굴었죠
I liked him, so I pretended
to be older.
자꾸 마실 것을 주더라고요
He kept giving me drinks.
이상한 기분을 느끼기 시작했고
I started to feel funny,
그가 저보고 누워야 하는지 물었어요
So he asked me if I
needed to lie down.
위층으로 가는 걸 도와줬어요. 그 다음이요?
He helped me upstairs. And the rest?
아빠가 그를 변호하고 있죠 지금
누가 한 짓을 아빠도 알죠
Well, you're defending him now;
you know what he does.
정신을 차리기가 어려웠어요
I was barely awake for any of it.
제가 아는 건 다음날
All I knew the next day
뭔가 역겨운 일이 제게 일어났다는 거죠
Was that something sick had happened to
me.
신문에서 아버지 사건을 보고 깨달았어요
When I read about your case in the
papers,
그 놈이 얼마나 많은 여자들에게 그랬는지
When I realized how many other
girls he'd done it to,
어쩌면 제가 막을 수도 있었을텐데
How maybe I could have stopped it all
제가 만약 용감해서 뭐라도 말했다면
If I had been braver and
said something,
이 모든 게 시작된 시점이죠
Well, that's when all this started.
죄송해요, 아빠
I'm sorry, daddy.
아빠에겐 뭐라도 말해야 했어요
I should have said something to you.
검사님
Sir.
정말이지....
I've...
죄송해요
I'm so sorry.
지난 밤에 꿈을 꿨는데요
I had a dream last night,
거기서....
And in it...
모든 걸 목격했어요
: I saw ev-everything.
이제 왜 그러셨는지 알겠어요
Now I know why you did what you did.
어제 제가 모자라게 굴어서
정말 죄송해요
I'm so sorry if I was
short with you yesterday,
아리아나에게 일어날 일은 정말 유감이에요
So sorry about what happened to arianna...
검사님 부부에게도요
To you and lily.
모든 게 다
For everything.
고맙네
Thank you.
꽤나 무거운 짐이었지
It's been quite a burden.
가장 힘들었던 건
내 아내에게 숨겨왔던 거지
The hardest part has been
keeping my wife in the dark.
불행히도, 이젠 그런 거 같군
Unfortunately, it looks like that's...
선택권이 없어
No longer an option.
출두하실 거예요?
You are gonna come forward?
내게 달리 방법이 있다고는 생각안하네
I don't think I really have a choice.
조만간 모두 정리해야겠지
I should have put it all together sooner.
그 놈이 사방에 남긴 부고기사...
The obituaries that he
was leaving everywhere...
그가 전말을 알게 된 거지
That's how he figured it all out--
감옥에서 그 기사를 우연히 발견했겠지
He must have come across one in prison
사진 속의 그 앨 보고
놀란 그놈을 상상해보게
And when he saw her picture,
imagine his surprise
자신이 강간한 사람이
When he realized that he raped
자기 변호사의 딸이란 걸 깨닫고 말일세
The daughter of his own defense attorney.
기자회견을 부를 예정이야
I'm gonna call a press conference
내일 오후 늦게
Tomorrow, late afternoon,
내가 한 짓을 인정하려고
Admit what I did.
아내는 친구들과 여행 중이야
Lily's away on a trip with some friends.
먼저 아내에게 말하고 싶군
I want to speak with her first.
그 후에 기자들에게 말해야지
After that, I'll speak with the press.
다행히 기자회견이 있을 거라는 사실은
Hopefully, the fact that there's going to be
거윈씨를 하루쯤은
A press conference will be enough
격리시키기에 충분할거라는 게지
To keep mr. Gerwin at bay for a day.
이곳이 그리울 걸세
I'm gonna miss this place.
실례 좀 하자
Regal man: Excuse me.
이건 네 거야
This is for you.
우와, 벌써 $92.18를 제 몫으로?
Wow. You already have my, uh, $92.18?
아니, 네가 어제 준 그 돈이야
No, it's just what you gave me yesterday.
가질 수 없어
I can't keep it.
네가 뭐라고 하든
I don't care what you say.
저기 말이다
You know, uh,
내가 몇 주간 이 짓만 해왔는데
I've only been doing this
for a couple of weeks.
자랑스럽지 않아
I'm not proud of it.
어, 한동안 일을 안했거든
It's just, uh, I haven't worked in a while,
돈이 조금이라도 들어오길 바랬는데
And I was hoping to get a
little bit of money coming in.
사실 내가 받은 돈은
네 돈 38달러가 전부야
But the truth is, your $38 was all I got,
엄.....나 어린애한테는 사기안쳐
And, uh, I didn't set out
to swindle little girls.
그럼 왕자가 아니라고요?
So you're not a prince?
왜 그렇게 차려입었는데요?
why are you dressed like that?
브리짓?
Bridgette?
그 일 다 마치고,
나 좀 도와주겠니?
When you're done with those,
would you come help me
어린이 섹션으로 와, 알았지?
In the children's section, please?
예, 알았어요
Yeah, sure.
저기, 에이킨 선생님
Um, miss aiken,
여기는 아반투 왕자예요
This is prince abantu.
나이지리아에서 왔어요
He's from nigeria.
만나서 반가워요
Nice to meet you.
예, 저도요
Yeah, you, too.
잘 가세요
Bye.
안녕
Bye-bye.
그럼 적어도
Well, at least
드부아가 여인네 중 한명은
일하는 게 행복하군.
One of the dubois women
is happy in her work.
브리짓이 도서관에서 일하는 걸 좋아해
Bridgette loves working
at the library.
당신이 거기에 대해 대화도 못하는 걸
She doesn't even mind the fact
걔는 심지어 신경도 안써
That you can't really talk in there.
도서관 일이 끝나가는 게 싫을 거래
Will hate to see it end.
갖가지 사람들을 만나고
Meets all kinds of interesting people.
심지어는 젊은 여자가
이메일 계정을 만드는 것도 도와줬대
Even helped a nice young girl
set up an e-mail account.
음?
Hmm?
아이 참, 브리짓 드부아
사서 대표가 돼다?
Come on, bridgette dubois,
librarian at large?
적어도 한번은 웃기 좋은 거 아냐?
Isn't that good for at least a smile?
흠, 아닌가 보군
Hmm. Well, I guess not.
사실은....
Hey, come on, I mean...
이 괴물이 이렇게 도망간다는 생각을 견디기 힘들어
I just, I can't stand the thought of
this monster getting away with this,
드발로스는 직업도, 면허도 잃게 되고
The thought of devalos
losing his job, his license.
그분이 실수한 걸 알지만
Look, I know he made a mistake,
진실을 말하자면,
우리 딸 중의 하나가 그랬다면
But the truth is, if that had
been one of our daughters,
나도 똑같은 일을 했을 거야
I would've done the same thing.
그 개놈자식을 죽이지 않은 것만 봐도
I think he showed remarkable restraint
그는 엄청난 절제심을 보여줬어
In not murdering the son of a bitch.
보이죠? 쉬워요
See? It's easy.
이제 원하는 누구에게든
이메일을 쓸 수 있어요
Now you can write
e-mails to whoever you want.
와우, 고맙다
Wow. Thanks.
되게 똑똑하구나
You're a very smart kid.
예, 그런 말 많이 들어요
Yeah, well, I get that a lot.
한가지 더 도와줄 수 있니?
Actually, can you help
me with one more thing?
타자를 잘 못 쳐서 그래
I'm not a very good typist.
난 마치 엄지 열 개를 갖고 있는 거 같아
I always feel like I have ten thumbs.
날 위해서 이메일 하나 타이핑해주지 않겠니?
Is there any way you could
type up an e-mail for me?
화내지 마세요
Don't be upset with me.
아리아나
Arianna...
아리아나, 무슨 말이에요?
Arianna, what are you talking about?
여기서 뭐하는 거예요?
What are you doing here?
당신의 딸에게 이메일을 타이핑하게 했어요
That e-mail I had your little girl type...
탐 하퍼라는 범죄조직 보스에게 편지가 갔어요
It went to a crime boss named tom harper.
윌리엄 거윈은 조직범죄 사건을
증언하는 데 동의해서
William gerwin got his
parole by agreeing to testify
가석방을 얻었죠
In an organized crime case.
거윈은 탐 하퍼의 심복 한명을 골로 보냈어요
He sent away one of tom
harper's top lieutenants.
하퍼는 누가 밀고했는지 몰랐죠
Harper never knew who the snitch was.
방금까지는요
That is, until now.
세상에, 그럼 당신은
Oh, my god, you do know
그 사람이 거윈에게 뭘 하려는지 알아요?
What that man is gonna
do to gerwin, don't you?
당연하죠
Absolutely.
헌데, 벌써 했어요
And by the way, he's already done it.
거윈이 이미 죽었어요?
Gerwin is already dead?
한시간 전에 일어난 일이죠
It happened about an hour ago.
그 자는 내게서 모든 걸 앗아 갔어요
That man took everything from me.
그가 저희 아버지에게서도 모든 걸
There's no way I could let him take
빼앗으려는 건 놔둘 수 없어요
Everything from my dad, too.
아버지가 하신 일은 비밀로 남길 원해요
I want what he did to remain a secret.
확실히 그럴 거예요
Well, I'm sure it will.
이제 아마도
Now... Maybe...
누가 알 이유가 없으니까요
Maybe there's no reason
for anyone to know now.
그래요
Good.
하지만 진실을 마땅히 알아야 하는 분이 계세요
But there is one person who
deserves to know the truth...
진실을 알고 싶어하는 분이요
Who needs to know the truth.
부탁 좀 들어주실래요?
Will you do something for me?
아버지가 저를 위해 해주시길
Get my father to do something for me?
아빠, 사랑해요
I love you, dad.
사랑해요, 엄마
And I love you, mom.
"두분 모두 엄청난 사랑을 주셨고“
Devalos & arianna:
"you both gave me so much love,
"제가 가는 곳 어디든지
그 사랑을 안고 갑니다“
"and I'm taking that with
me wherever I'm going.
"서로에게 이걸 보여 주세요“
Devalos : "now you'll need
to give it to each other.
"안녕히, 아빠“
"goodbye, daddy.
"안녕히, 엄마“
"goodbye, mommy.
“사랑합니다, 아리아나 올림”
I love you. Arianna."
Captioning sponsored by
cbs paramount network
television
Captioning sponsored by
cbs paramount network
television